Guide to the George Jean Nathan collection, 1913-1958
Nathan, George Jean collection, 1913-1958
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
George Jean Nathan collection, 1913-1958.
4615
George Jean, Nathan 1882-1958.
14.7 linear ft.
Manuscripts, correspondence, articles, clippings, and photographs.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Manuscripts, correspondence, printed newspaper articles, clippings, and photographs by, to, or about Nathan, documenting his career as theater critic, author, and editor of the literary newspaper The American Spectator. Includes manuscripts for books and articles by Nathan; extensive correspondence concerning dealings with publishers, authors, and producers; letters from readers and fellow writers commenting on Nathan's work, including letters on the American Mercury and the American Spectator; and manuscripts of plays by other writers, including 18 plays by William Saroyan and 10 by Sean O'Casey. Also included are manuscripts and galley proofs for Nathan's annual Theatre Book of the Year (9 vols., 1942-1951).
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
American theater critic, author, and editor. He edited the magazine Smart Set with H.L. Mencken from 1914-1923, founded and co-edited the magazine American Mercury with Mencken, and was one of the founding editors of the literary newspaper American Spectator.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Manuscripts, correspondence, printed newspaper articles, clippings, and photographs by, to, or about Nathan, documenting his career as theater critic, author, and editor of the literary newspaper The American Spectator. Includes manuscripts for books and articles by Nathan; extensive correspondence concerning dealings with publishers, authors, and producers; letters from readers and fellow writers commenting on Nathan's work, including letters on the American Mercury and the American Spectator; and manuscripts of plays by other writers, including 18 plays by William Saroyan and 10 by Sean O'Casey. Also included are manuscripts and galley proofs for Nathan's annual Theatre Book of the Year (9 vols., 1942-1951).
Also included are hundreds of letters from H.L. Mencken, ranging in date from 1925-1955; 129 letters from Eugene O'Neill, dating from 1919-1949; and 58 letters from William Saroyan, ranging from 1928-1957. Other correspondents include Sherwood Anderson, James Branch Cabell, Gordon Craig, Theodore Dreiser, the Encyclopaedia Britannica, St. John Greer Ervine; Alfred A. Knopf, Inc.; Sinclair Lewis, Carlotta O'Neill, Carl Sandburg, and Jim Tully. Also included are many photographs of Nathan and several of H.L. Mencken, Eugene O'Neill, Sean O'Casey, Lillian Gish, and others.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Nathan, George Jean,1882-1958.; Anderson, Sherwood, 1876-1941.; Cabell, James Branch, 1879-1958.; Craig, Edward Gordon, 1872-1966.; Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945.; Ervine, St. John G.(St. John Greer), b. 1883.; Gish, Lillian, 1893-1993.; Lewis, Sinclair, 1885-1951.; Mencken, H. L.(Henry Louis), 1880-1956.; Mencken, H. L.(Henry Louis), 1880-1956.; Nathan, George Jean, 1882-1958.; O'Casey, Sean, 1880-1964.; O'Casey, Sean, 1880-1964.; O'Neill, Carlotta.; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953.; Sandburg, Carl, 1878-1967.; Saroyan, William, 1908-; Tully, Jim.; Alfred A. Knopf, Inc.; Encyclopaedia Britannica, inc.
Titles:
American spectator.; American mercury.
Subjects:
Theater--United States--20th century.; Theater--United States--History and criticism.; American periodicals.; Publishers and publishing--United States.; Authors and publishers--United States.; Authors and readers--United States.; Authors, American.; Theater critics--United States.
Form and Genre Terms:
Portraits.; Photographs.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
RELATED MATERIALS
Large book collection also held in the repository, including many works by Nathan and works of other writers in copies inscribed to Nathan.
Related material in the Theodore Dreiser Collection, Department of Rare Books, Cornell University Library.
COLLECTION ARRANGEMENT
Organized into the following series: photographs; letters by Nathan; clippings; printed articles; manuscripts; Theatre Book manuscripts; letters to Nathan.
Letters by Nathan arranged in chronological order; manuscripts, alphabetically by title; Theatre Book manuscripts, in chronological order; letters to Nathan, alphabetically by correspondent.
CONTAINER LIST
- George Nathan articles (Box 1, Folder 1-11)
- Beware of Parents (ts.) (Box 1, Folder 12-16)
- Beware of Parents (galley ) (Box 1, Folder 17-18)
- The Avon Flows (Box 1, Folder 19-21)
- The Bachelor Life (Box 1, Folder 22-24)
- Document concerning his [Nathan] rights: "The American Credo" and "Heliogabalus" rights of publicty, etc. (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Encyclopedia of the Theatre (ts.) (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Encyclopedia of the Theatre (ms. and annotated proofs) (Box 1, Folder 27-36)
- The Entertainment of a Nation (ms. and annotated proofs (Box 1, Folder 37-41)
- The Entertainment of a Nation (ts.) (Box 2, Folder 1-5)
- The Entertainment of a Nation (galley) (Box 2, Folder 6-9)
- Morals (Box 2, Folder 10-11)
- Miscellanea 1. Books (Box 2, Folder 12-13)
- Miscellanea 2. Columns (Box 2, Folder 14-16)
- Miscellanea 3. Articles (Box 2, Folder 17-18)
- Miscellanea 4. Fragments (Box 2, Folder 19-24)
- Nathan and Mencken - Heliogabalus (ts.) (Box 2, Folder 25-26)
- First Nights and Passing Judgements (Box 2, Folder 27-31)
- Passing Judgements (ts. and galley) (Box 2, Folder 32-33)
- The Morning After the First Night (galley) (Box 3, Folder 1-4)
- The Morning After the First Night (ts.) (Box 3, Folder 5-8)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ms.) (Box 3, Folder 9-12)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (galley), 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 13-16)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ts.), 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 17-20)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ms.), 1942-1943 (Box 3, Folder 21-27)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (galley), 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 28-31)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ts.), 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 1-4)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ms.), 1943-1944 (Box 4, Folder 5-10)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ms.), 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 11-17)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (galley), 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 18-20)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ts.), 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 21-25)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ms.), 1945-1946 (Box 4, Folder 26-30)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ts.), 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 1-5)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (galley), 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 6-9)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ms.), 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 10-14)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ts.), 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 15-18)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (galley), 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 19-21)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ts.), 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 22-25)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ms.), 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 1-5)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (galley), 1947-1948 (Box 6, Folder 6-9)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ts.), 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 10-13)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ms.), 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 14-16)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (galley), 1948-1949 (Box 6, Folder 17-18)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ms.), 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 19-20)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (galley), 1949-1950 (Box 6, Folder 21-23)
- The Critic and the Drama(annotated pages), n.d. (Box 6, Folder 24)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ts.), 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 1-4)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (galley), 1950-1051 (Box 7, Folder 5-11)
- The Theatre Book of the Year (ms.), 1950-1951 (Box 7, Folder 12-14)
- Theatre Week (Box 7, Folder 15-18)
- Hanna, Mark June 16, 19 57, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 20)
- Hendrickson, Mr. May 7, 1945, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 21)
- Dreiser, Theodore Dec. 21, 1933, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 22)
- Greenwich Village Theatre Jan. 24, 1924, 1924 (Box 7, Folder 23)
- Josephy, Mr. Nov. 28, 1921, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 24)
- Knopf, Alfred A., n.d. (Box 7, Folder 25)
- Laurence, Dan H. Dec. 9, 1944; June 20, 1950, 1944, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 26)
- Margo, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 27)
- Mencken, Henry Louis, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 28)
- Mizener, Arthur Jan. 13, 1950, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 29)
- The Mask Publisher Aug. 2, ?, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 30)
- Musical Courier - editor Nov. 10, 1916, 1916 (Box 7, Folder 31)
- O'Casey, Sean Aug. 25, 1932 to Dec. 14, 1933, 1932-1933 (Box 7, Folder 32)
- O'Casey, Sean April 5, 1938 to Nov. 30, 1946, 1938-1946 (Box 7, Folder 33)
- O'Casey, Sean Feb. 23, 1947 to Oct. 26, 1952, 1947-1952 (Box 7, Folder 34)
- O'Casey, Sean Jan. 9, 1953 to June ?, 1957, 1953-1957 (Box 7, Folder 35)
- O'Casey, Sean, n.d. (Box 7, Folder 36)
- Prescott, F.C. April 14, 1922, 1922 (Box 7, Folder 37)
- Silberman, Joseph S. June 16, 1957, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 38)
- Smith, Richard R. Sept. 9. 1932, 1932 (Box 7, Folder 39)
- Van Loon, Hendrik William Dec. 1, 1933, 1933 (Box 7, Folder 40)
- Spier, Franklin June 1 to July 19, 1921, 1921 (Box 7, Folder 41)
- General (Box 7, Folder 42-72)
- [unidentified]: "Cleaning Up the Town" (Box 8, Folder 1-3)
- Brennan, Frederick H.: "We fought at Arques" (Box 8, Folder 4)
- Bowers, William: "Billy Doo" (Box 8, Folder 5)
- Adelman, Louis: "Coke Night on the Corner" (Box 8, Folder 6)
- Curtiss, Thomas Quinn: The World of George Jean Nathan (book) (Box 8, Folder 7-10)
- Priestley, J.B.: "They Came to a City" (Box 8, Folder 11)
- Osborn, Paul: A New Play (untitled new play) (Box 8, Folder 12)
- Levin, Meyer: "Compulsion" (Box 8, Folder 13-14)
- Levy, Bert: "Watch Closely" (Box 8, Folder 15)
- Molloy, Michael J.: "The King of Friday's Men" (Box 8, Folder 16)
- Gordon, Ruth: "Years Ago" (Box 8, Folder 17)
- Bon-Diable, Robert: (from the French of Alfred de Musset) "Gamiani" of "Two Nights of Excess" (Box 12, Folder 1)
- Greville, Eden E.: "The Realist" (Box 8, Folder 18)
- Johnston, Denis: "The Golden Cuckoo" (Box 12, Folder 2)
- O'Neill, Eugene: "Dynamo" (Box 8, Folder 19)
- O'Neill, Eugene: "Lazarus Laughed" (Box 8, Folder 20)
- O'Neill, Eugene: "Marco Millions" (Box 8, Folder 21)
- Fischman, Charles: "You and I Will Meet" A Shavian Opera (Box 8, Folder 22)
- Hemlely, Cecil and Henry Brant"Miss O'Grady" Theatre Opera (Box 8, Folder 23)
- Lewis, Sinclair: "Publish Glad Tidings" (Box 8, Folder 24)
- Hicks, Seymour: "Sleeping Partners" (Box 8, Folder 25)
- Taylor, Marian: "No Concern of Yours" (Box 12, Folder 3)
- Taylor, Marian: "No Concern of Yours" (Box 12, Folder 4)
- Riva, Humberto: "The Other Side of Life" (Box 8, Folder 26)
- Romero, Ramon: "Mrs. Lincoln" (Box 8, Folder 27)
- Roussen, Andre: "The Ostrich Eggs" (Box 8, Folder 28)
- Lothar Smith: "Only a Dream" (Box 12, Folder 5)
- Noel, Sterling: I Killed Stalin (book galley) (Box 9, Folder 1)
- O'Casey, Sean: "The Star Turns Red" (Box 9, Folder 2)
- O'Casey, Sean: "Purple Dust" (Box 9, Folder 3)
- O'Casey, Sean: "Warald on Wallpaper" (Box 9, Folder 4)
- O'Casey, Sean: "Time to Go" (Box 9, Folder 5)
- O'Casey, Sean: "Red Roses for Me" (Box 9, Folder 6)
- O'Casey, Sean: "The End of the Beginning" (Box 9, Folder 7)
- O'Casey, Sean: "The Bishop's Bonfire" (Box 9, Folder 8)
- O'Casey, Sean: "Bedtime Story" (Box 9, Folder 9)
- Saroyan, William: "The Time of Your Life: (Box 9, Folder 10)
- Saroyan, Willam: "Sweeney in the Trees" (Box 9, Folder 11)
- Saroyan, Willam: "Don't Go Away Mad" (Box 9, Folder 12)
- Saroyan, Willam: "The Hero of the World" (Box 9, Folder 13)
- Saroyan, Willam: "Across the Board on Tomorrow Morning" (Box 9, Folder 14)
- Saroyan, Willam: "Afton Water" (Box 9, Folder 15)
- Saroyan, Willam: "Arena and Referee" (Box 9, Folder 16)
- Saroyan, Willam: "As I Live and Breathe" (Box 9, Folder 17)
- Saroyan, Willam: "A Decent Birth, A Happy Funeral" (Box 9, Folder 18)
- Saroyan, Willam: "Fathers and Sons" (Box 9, Folder 19)
- Saroyan, Willam: "Bang! Bang! You're Dead!" (Box 9, Folder 20)
- Saroyan, Willam: "The White Swans of the River Liffey" (Box 9, Folder 21)
- Saroyan, Willam: "The Light Fantastic" (Box 9, Folder 22)
- Saroyan, Willam: "Talking to You" (Box 9, Folder 23)
- Saroyan, Willam: "Once Around the Block" (Box 9, Folder 24)
- Saroyan, Willam: "Jim Dandy" (Box 9, Folder 25)
- Saroyan, Willam: "Get Away Old Man" (Box 9, Folder 26)
- Drus, Paul: "Hexaenboo" (Box 9, Folder 26a)
- [unidentified]: "An Affair of Stars" (Box 9, Folder 27)
- [unidentified}: "The Fairy Tale" (Box 9, Folder 28)
- Abdullah, Achmed 1 letter, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 29)
- Abelow, A. R. 1 letter, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 30)
- Academy of Arts and Scientists 1 letter, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 31)
- Adamic, Louis, 1899-1951. 1 letter, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 32)
- Adams, Edith 1 letter, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 33)
- Adams, James Truslow, 1878-1949. 1 letter, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 34)
- Ade, George, 1966-1944. 1 letter, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 36)
- Agate, James Evershed, 1877-1947. 8 letters, 1932-1946 (Box 9, Folder 37)
- Agins, Claire 1 letter, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 38)
- Aldrich, Richard Stoddard, 1902-1941 1 letter, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 39)
- Algase, Gertrude 1 letter, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 40)
- Alicat Book Shop 1 letter, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 41)
- Allen, Leroy 1 letter, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 42)
- Allen, Robert 3 letters, 1932, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 43)
- The American Mercury 1 letter, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 44)
- Ames, Richard Sheridan 2 letters, 1935, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 45)
- Ames, Winthrop, 1871-1937. 3 letters, 1914, 1916, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 46)
- Anderson, David Merrill 1 letter, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 47)
- Anderson, John, 1896-1943. 1 letter, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 48)
- Anderson, Paul Y., 1893-1938. 1 letter, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 49)
- Anderson, Sherwood, 1876-1941. 17 letters, 1932-1938, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 50)
- Anderton, Daisy 1 letter, 1919 (Box 9, Folder 51)
- Angoff, Charles 3 letters, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 52)
- Anthony, Katharine Susan, 1877-1965. 3 letters, 1932-1934 (Box 9, Folder 53)
- Asbury, Herbert 2 letters 1 letter, 1925, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 54)
- Atkinson, Brooks, 1894-. 1 letter, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 55)
- Atlas, Charles 1 letter, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 56)
- Austin, Mary, 1868-1934. 1 letter, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 57)
- Aylee 1 letter, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 58)
- Bacon, Pat 1 letter, 1949 (Box 9, Folder 59)
- Badger, Richard G. 1 letter, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 60)
- Bagby, Steadman 1 letter, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 61)
- Bair, Fred 1 letter, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 62)
- Baldwin, Faith 1 letter, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 63)
- Balseiro, José A. 1 letter, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 64)
- Banks, James L., Jr. 1 letter, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 65)
- Baring, Maurice 3 letters, 1923, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 66)
- Barnes, Harry Elmer, 1889-1968. 3 letters, 1929-1937 (Box 9, Folder 67)
- Barrett, Richmond 1 letter, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 68)
- Barron, Mark, 1905-1960. 1 letter, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 69)
- Beer, Thomas, 1889-1940. 2 letters, 1933, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 70)
- Beesley, J. C., Jr. 1 letter, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 71)
- Belgion, Montgomery 1 letter, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 72)
- Benedict, Ruth 1 letter, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 73)
- Benham, Ruth 1 letter, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 74)
- Benson, Stella 1 letter plus article ms., 1932, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 75)
- Bentley, Eric Russell, 1916-. article about O'Neill, ca. 1952 (Box 9, Folder 76)
- Berger, Jeanette 1 letter, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 77)
- Bigley, Isabel 1 letter, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 78)
- Bird, Edward 1 letter, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 79)
- Blau, Bernard 1 letter, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 80)
- Block, Martin Fiddler 1 letter, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 81)
- Bluemner, Oscar 1 letter, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 82)
- Bolger, William 1 letter, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 83)
- Boni and Liveright Publishers 4 letters, 1923-1925 (Box 9, Folder 84)
- Borges, Fredericka (Mrs. M. V.) 1 letter, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 85)
- Bourgeois, Maurice 1 letter, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 86)
- Bowdoin Chapter of Delta Upsilon 1 letter, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 87)
- Bowdoin College 1 letter, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 88)
- Bowers, William 1 letter, 1943 (Box 9, Folder 89)
- Boyd, Julian Parks, 1903-. 2 letters, 1951, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 90)
- Bradford, Gamaliel, 1863-1932. 1 letter, 1923 (Box 9, Folder 91)
- Bradish, C. R. 7 letters, 1926-56 (Box 9, Folder 92)
- Bradley, David 1 letter, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 93)
- Brady, James A. 1 letter, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 94)
- Brady, William A. 1 letter, 1913 (Box 9, Folder 95)
- Brandeis, Florence 1 letter, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 96)
- Brandeis University Creative Arts Awards 1 letter, 1958 (Box 9, Folder 97)
- Brandt, Carl 2 letters, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 98)
- Brandt, Erdmann Neumiester, 1893-1966. 1 letter [missing], 1922 (Box 9, Folder 99)
- Breen, Robert 1 letter, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 100)
- British Broadcasting Corporation 1 letter, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 101)
- Brockett, Frances Halley 1 letter, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 102)
- Bronson, Benjamin 1 letter, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 103)
- Brooke, Jocelyn 1 letter, 1953 (Box 9, Folder 104)
- Brooks, Lawrence 1 letter, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 105)
- Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963. 1 letter, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 106)
- Brown, Allen B. 2 letters, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 107)
- Brown, Arthur William, 1881. 1 letter, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 108)
- Brown, Gilmor 1 letter, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 109)
- Brown, Grace 1 letter, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 110)
- Brown, Ivor 1 letter, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 111)
- Brown, John Mason, 1900-. 2 letters, 1943, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 112)
- [Brulain?], Mabel 1 letter, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 113)
- Brumm, John Lewis 1 letter, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 114)
- Buchanan, Thompson, -1937. 2 letters, 1911 (Box 9, Folder 115)
- Buckley, Edmund 1 letter, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 116)
- Burgess, E.W. 1 letter, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 117)
- Burke, Thomas, 1848-1925. 4 letters, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 118)
- Burnett, Whit, 1899-. 3 letters, 1942, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 119)
- Burr, Walter 1 letter, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 120)
- Cabell, James Branch, 1879-1958. 17 letters, 1921-1932 (Box 9, Folder 121)
- Cabell, James Branch 25 letters, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 122)
- Cabell, James Branch 27 letters, 1934, 1935, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 123)
- Cadillac Publishing Company 1 letter, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 124)
- Caffrey, John Gordon 2 letters, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 125)
- Cahn, Albert, Jr. 1 letter, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 126)
- Caldwell, Erskine, 1903-1987. 1 letter, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 127)
- Callahan, Clayton 1 letter, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 128)
- Callis, Theodore Edwin, 1908-. 1 letter, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 129)
- Campbell, Jack 2 letters, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 130)
- Canby, Henry Seidel, 1878-1961. 1 letter, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 131)
- Capalbo, Carmen 1 letter, 1954 (Box 9, Folder 132)
- Cardwell, Ann B. 1 letter, 1930 (Box 9, Folder 133)
- Carroll, Cliff 1 letter, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 134)
- Carroll, Diahann 1 letter, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 135)
- Carroll, Paul Vincent, 1900-1968. 1 letter also, copy of play "The Strings, My Lord, Are False", 1941 (Box 9, Folder 136)
- Carroll, Paul Vincent 1 letter also, copy of play "The Wise have Not Spoken", 1948 (Box 9, Folder 137)
- Carroll, Paul Vincent 8 letters, 1938-1954, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 138)
- Case, Frank[?] 1 letter, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 139)
- Casey and McConner 2 letters, 1936 (Box 9, Folder 140)
- Cassidy, Claudia 1 letter, 1945 (Box 9, Folder 141)
- Central Press Association 1 letter, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 142)
- Cerf, Bennett Alfred, 1898-. 3 letters, 1936, 1942, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 143)
- Chamberlain, John Rensselaer, 1903-. 1 letter, 1951 (Box 9, Folder 144)
- Chambrum, Jacques 1 letter, 1934 (Box 9, Folder 145)
- Chase, William D. 1 letter, 1950 (Box 9, Folder 146)
- Chase, William Sheaft, 1858-1940. 1 letter, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 147)
- Chatterji, N. 1 letter, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 148)
- Chesapeake and Ohio Railway Company, 1 letter, 1948 (Box 9, Folder 149)
- Chicago Sun, 1 letter, 1947 (Box 9, Folder 150)
- Child, Maude P. 1 letter, 1926 (Box 9, Folder 151)
- Chisholm, Joseph 1 letter, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 152)
- Chittenden, Gerald, 1882-., 1927 (Box 9, Folder 153)
- Clare Tree Major Children's Theatre 1 letter, 1940 (Box 9, Folder 154)
- Classics Club, The 1 letter, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 155)
- Cleland, Ralph Erskine, 1892-. 1 letter, 1853 (Box 9, Folder 156)
- Clendening, Dr. Logan, 1884-1945. 2 letters, 1932 (Box 9, Folder 157)
- Cline, Leonard 1 letter, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 158)
- Clautier, Eunyse 1 letter, 1925 (Box 9, Folder 159)
- Clow, Stephen G. 1 letter, 1921 (Box 9, Folder 160)
- Cochran, Charles B. 2 letters, 1929, 1938 (Box 9, Folder 161)
- Cohan, George M., 1878-1942. 1 letter, 1941 (Box 9, Folder 162)
- Cohn, Art 1 letter, 1956 (Box 9, Folder 163)
- College Humor 2 letters, 1927, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 164)
- Colley, C 1 letter, 1929 (Box 9, Folder 165)
- Cools, G. Victor 1 letter, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 166)
- Cooper, Grace 1 letter, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 167)
- Copeland, Virginia 1 letter, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 168)
- Cornell University Press 3 letters, 1941, 1942 (Box 9, Folder 169)
- Corrigan, C. C. 1 letter, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 170)
- Coton, A. V. 4 letters, 1945, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 171)
- Coverly, Harvey and Erskine 1 letter, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 172)
- Cowles, David S. 1 letter, 1946 (Box 9, Folder 173)
- Craig, Edward Gordon, 1872-1966. 14 letters, 1916-1920 (Box 9, Folder 174)
- Craig, Edward Gordon 22 letters, 1921-1923 (Box 9, Folder 175)
- Craig, Edward Gordon 25 letters, 1924-1935 (Box 9, Folder 176)
- Craig, Edward Gordon 8 letters, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 177)
- Craven, H. T. 1 letter, n.d. (Box 9, Folder 178)
- Craven, Thomas, 1889-1950. 1 letter, 1933 (Box 9, Folder 179)
- Critics' Circle 4 letters, 1926, 1935, 1937 (Box 9, Folder 180)
- Crockett, Albert Stevens, 1872-. 1 letter, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 181)
- Crolins, Ted 1 letter, 1955 (Box 9, Folder 182)
- Cross, Austin F. 1 letter, 1957 (Box 9, Folder 183)
- Crowninshield, Frank 1 letter, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 184)
- Curley, William, A. -1955. 7 letters, 1943-1952 (Box 10, Folder 1)
- Current History Magazine 1 letter, 1934 (Box 10, Folder 2)
- Curtiss, Thomas Quinn 2 letters, 1946 (Box 10, Folder 3)
- Daily Express 3 letters, 1928, 1929, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 4)
- Daily Mail 3 letters, 1925, 1927, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 5)
- Darrin, Mrs. Mary V. 1 letter, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Darrow, Clarence S., 1857-1938. 2 letters; typed ms., 1932, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 7)
- David, Benjamin 1 letter, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 8)
- Davis, R. H. 2 letters, 1911, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 9)
- Day, Edmund Ezra, 1883-1951. 1 letter, 1948 (Box 10, Folder 10)
- Daye, Stephen, Inc. 1 letter, 1945 (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Deacon, William Arthur 1 letter, 1933 (Box 10, Folder 12)
- DeCasseres, Benjamin, - 1945. 2 letters, 1932 (Box 10, Folder 13)
- Deerey, Teresa 1 letter, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 14)
- de Kruif, Paul, 1890-. 2 letters, 1943, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 15)
- Delaney, John C. 1 letter, 1949 (Box 10, Folder 16)
- De Lavallade, Carmen 1 letter, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 17)
- Dempsey, Jack, 1895-. 1 letter, 1935 (Box 10, Folder 18)
- Dent, Alan 13 letters, 1931-1955 (Box 10, Folder 19)
- Dessanet, A. Paul J. 1 letter, 1925 (Box 10, Folder 20)
- Deutsch, Helen 1 letter, 1938 (Box 10, Folder 21)
- DeVines, Peter Hugh 1 letter, 1928 (Box 10, Folder 22)
- Devoe, Alan 1 letter, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 23)
- Dillinghan, Charles Bancroft, 1868-1934. 1 letter, 1924 (Box 10, Folder 24)
- Dobell, Isabel 2 letters, 1945, 1950 (Box 10, Folder 25)
- Dodd, Loring Holmes 1 letter, 1936 (Box 10, Folder 26)
- Dolan, Ken 1 letter, 1937 (Box 10, Folder 27)
- Dos Passos, John, 1896-1970. "Notes on the Back of a Passport", n.d. (Box 10, Folder 28)
- Doubleday, Doran & Co. 1 letter, 1930 (Box 10, Folder 29)
- Dowling, Eddie, 1894-. 1 letter, 1957 (Box 10, Folder 30)
- Downing, Robert 1 letter, 1951 (Box 10, Folder 31)
- Drake, Marie 1 letter, 1928 (Box 10, Folder 32)
- Dreiser, Theodore, 1871-1945. 13 letters, 1919-1931 (Box 10, Folder 33)
- Dreiser, Theodore 16 letters, 1932-1938 (Box 10, Folder 34)
- Dreiser, Theodore 37 letters/items, n.d. (Box 10, Folder 35)
- Drewry, John E. 1 letter, 1952 (Box 10, Folder 36)
- Drus, Paul 1 letter, 1940 (Box 10, Folder 37)
- Durant, Harry 1 letter, 1926 (Box 10, Folder 38)